Izabela J. Pikula Curriculum Vitae

5, Perryn House, Bromyard Avenue **Tel.:** 07975678836

London W3 7JD Email: <u>i.j.pikula@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: https://uk.linkedin.com/in/izabelapikula

GitHub: https://github.com/iza-pik

Creative **Front-End Developer** working with **React.js** to design responsive applications. Experienced translator, proofreader and translation/transcreation project manager with good **problem-solving skills** and an excellent **eye for detail**. Amateur photographer and painter. I am passionate about learning new skills and tackling new challenges.

Projects

- Personal Portfolio (<u>live demo</u> / <u>repository</u>)
- Calculator (<u>live demo</u> / <u>repository</u>)
- Weather App (live demo / repository)
- Game of Life (live demo / repository)
- Pizzeria Website
- Other

Skills

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript; basic Python
- React.js
- Git
- basic d3.js
- jQuery
- Bootstrap
- basic Photoshop
- CAT tools: SDL Studio 2019, Wordfast, Memsource

Work experience

March 2019 – ongoing

React Developer, Symposium OÜ, London

Working on a few projects in a team of React.js developers, in an Agile environment. Using GitHub to contribute to the code base of the project.

Building and styling components, routing to navigate components throughout the site.

April 2019 – ongoing

Translation Project Coordinator, Life Sciences, SDL plc, London

Working as part of the Life Sciences team in a multinational software localisation, translation and content management company. Coordinating translation projects, using Studio 2019 and internal tools.

Quoting, placing work – selecting vendors, managing queries, quality check, client delivery, review.

August 2013 - March 2019

Production Assistant, Smallworld Translation Services Ltd, London

Translation, proofreading and project management in the field of medicine and pharmaceutics

Medical and pharmaceutical translation (human and veterinary medicinal product information, clinical trial documentation, marketing authorisation procedures, technical manuals on medical equipment, etc.). Translation, proofreading and linguistic review of multilingual translation projects, ensuring that the documents supplied to the client meet all quality standards and formal requirements (such as norms and templates of the European Medicines Agency), in-house editing and formatting.

Managing the full project life-cycle, client communication and quoting.

August 2013 - March 2019

Freelance translator and proofreader

(EN, FR and ES into PL; PL, FR and ES into EN)

Translation, transcreation and proofreading services. Timely delivery of the correct and accurate target language version of original documents to the end client or a translation agency.

Projects:

- ads, newsletters, B2B / B2C communications for multinational corporations manufacturing electronics;
- training materials for managers of a large insurance company;
- website localisation (e.g. international telecommunications corporation, coach services company);
- marketing material (luxury cosmetics and confectionery and electronics brands);
- hospital discharge reports.

April-June 2014

Trainee Polish Translator

Polish Translation Unit at the General Secretariat of the European Parliament in Luxembourg

Translating and proofreading a variety of official documents related to European affairs, such as: official letters, agendas of meetings, minutes, notices to Members, petitions from citizens, parliamentary amendments as well as texts published on the "Europarl" website and the MEP's Portal.

Izabela J. Pikula Curriculum Vitae

I also contributed to a terminology project on the subject of human rights in the Terminology Coordination Unit. I participated in numerous seminars and comprehensive training on translation-related IT tools (SDL Studio 2014 an internal EP tools) and terminological databases (e.g. IATE, EUR-Lex), and took part in missions to Strasbourg and Brussels, and in visits to the other EU institutions and agencies (the European Commission, the Court of Justice, the Translation Centre for the Bodies of the EU, etc.).

April-July 2013 Transcreation Project Manager

Creative Culture Ltd, London

My role was to manage a large transcreation project into multiple languages for a multinational insurance company. This job also involved quality control, maintaining internal consistency tools, cooperating with the team, talent management, research, social media marketing (Twitter).

Before 2013 Voluntary work:

Part of "TED. Ideas worth spreading" translation team (www.ted.com): subtitling of TED conferences into Polish.

"Top Class in Science" international translation project, Norwich, UK (EN>PL translation of science olympiad quiz questions and answers and localisation of the website for the pilot project of a competition between several European countries).

Education

June 2019 Responsive Web Design Developer Certification (300 hours)

FreeCodeCamp

Sept. 2011 – Feb. 2013 MA with Distinction in Applied Translation Studies, University of East Anglia,

Norwich

Dissertation: "Close-up look on translation. Translation into Polish of a chapter from *Mastering Digital Photography* by Michael Freeman with commentary drawing on *skopos*"

Awarded a School of Language and Communication Studies Scholarship Participated in a series of workshops on legal, scientific, technical translation, adaptation and localisation

Extensive training in audiovisual translation (subtitling)

CAT tools, MT editing and translation project management training

Sept. 2007 – July 2011 BA with First Class Honours in Translation, Media with French and Spanish,

University of East Anglia, Norwich

School of Language and Communication Studies Annual Prize for outstanding

performance in the degree programme

Sept. 2009 – June 2010 Year-abroad academic research project

ERASMUS student in France and Spain:

Université Jean Moulin, Lyon

Universidad Antonio de Nebrija, Madrid

Languages

Native proficiency: Polish

Full professional proficiency: English

Spanish French

Elementary proficiency: Japanese

Other interests

Photography, painting, visual arts

Travel and culture